Finding Aid for Bird Family Papers, 1835-1914
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Bird Family Papers 1835-1914
Bird Family
1 linear ft.
85497 Aa 2
Bird family of Truago (now Trenton) in Wayne County, Michigan, later founders of Clayton in Lenawee County, Michigan. Papers, 1837-1857, of Chauncey Bird, including account of flight in 1811 from Litchfield, Connecticut, to escape persecution by Masons; papers, 1835-1873, of Reuben E. Bird, largely concerning operation of Clayton general store; and diary, scrapbook, and other papers of John E. Bird, state attorney general and supreme court justice.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Mr. Major Bird (donor no. 305 ) and came to the library in 1938 with a small addition in 1980.
The collection is open to research.
Subjects:
Bird General Store (Clayton, Mich.); Clayton (Mich.); Freemasonry--Michigan.; General stores--Michigan--Clayton.; Lenawee County (Mich.); Trenton (Mich.)
Contributors:
Bird, Chauncey.; Bird, John E. (John Everett), 1862-1928.; Bird, Reuben E. (Reuben Everett), 1811-1885.
Genre Terms:
Scrapbooks.; Diaries.
- Chauncey Bird
  - Papers, 1837-1857 (Box 1)
    (including letters from relatives about farm life in Michigan; and account of flight in 1811 from Litchfield, Conn. to escape persecution by Masons)
- Reuben E. Bird
  - Papers
    - 1835-1853 and 1861 (Box 1)
    - 1872-1874 (Box 1)
    - 1875-1880 (Box 1)
    - 1881-1882 (Box 1)
  - Legal materials concerning seizure of a horse owned by Bird, 1872 (Box 1)
  - Account book, 1870-1873 (Box 1)
  - Business cards and advertisements (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous (including newspaper obituary) (Box 1)
  - General store records
    - Account book
      - 1836-1843 (Box 1)
      - 1844-1835 (Box 1)
      - 1848-1853 (Box 1)
      - 1850-1860 (Box 1)
      - 1869-1873 (Box 1)
    - Cash book, 1866-1870 (Box 1)
      (volume later used as book of quotations)
    - Plats for Clayton, Mich., ca. 1838 (Box 1)
    - Tax assessment roll for Hudson Township, Lenawee County, 1840 (Box 1)
- John E. Bird
  - Diary, January-February 1872 and account book, 1874-1877 (Box 1)
  - Scrapbook containing obituaries of family and friends, ca. 1876-1914 (Box 1)
- Bird family
  - Receipts, mortgages, notes, etc., 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Anti-Masonic printed material (Box 1)